Inventory of the Papers of Edwin S. Cohen
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
Inventory of the Papers of Edwin S. Cohen
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
MSS 87-4
72 linear feet, or 160 boxes and 2 cartons
Edwin S. Cohen, an alumnus of the University of Virginia School of Law, served as Assistant Secretary of the Treasury for Tax Policy and as Under Secretary of the Treasury for the Nixon administration. Most of the documents in this collection relate to Cohen's service in the Department of the Treasury. In addition there is considerable documentation of his private law practice in New York and Washington, D.C. and of his teaching at the University of Virginia School of Law.
Administrative Information
Access
Access to some of the material in Series VII may be restricted. Otherwise, there are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Edwin S. Cohen was born in Richmond, Virginia, on September 27th, 1914. He grew up in that city and at age fifteen entered the University of Richmond. Three years later he entered law school at the University of Virginia where he was an excellent student and served on the editorial board of the Virginia Law Review. He received his law degree in 1936 before his twenty-first birthday.
After law school he went to New York and worked from 1936 to 1949 as an associate with Sullivan & Cromwell. There he began to specialize in taxation and investment matters and afterwards gave lectures on the subjects. In 1949 he formed the firm Root, Barrett, Cohen, Knapp and Smith with some of his former law classmates and continued doing tax work for the mutual fund industry. He remained with that practice until 1965.
Cohen had always been interested in teaching, and in 1963, Dean Hardy Dillard offered him the opportunity to teach law at his alma mater. For two terms he commuted from New York City to Charlottesville twice a month to teach a tax course. After the second course he was offered a visiting professorship, and a year later, an appointment to the faculty. In 1968 he was named to the Joseph M. Hartfield Chair.
In 1969 the Nixon administration designated him Assistant Secretary for Tax Policy to work with Secretary of Treasury David M. Kennedy and Under Secretary Charles E. Walker. In 1972 he was appointed Under Secretary of the Treasury and served in that position until his resignation in 1973.
After his stint in the Treasury Department Cohen resumed teaching at Virginia and practicing law with Covington & Burling in Washington, D.C. Later he became partner and senior counselor at the firm until his retirement in 1986.
Cohen served on numerous committees, task forces, councils, and clubs throughout his career. From the early 1950s he acted as consultant in various tax matters for the American Law Institute. In 1956 he became part of a seven-member advisory group for the House Ways and Means Committee to consider the revision of the corporate tax rules in the federal tax law. He drafted a revised statute and a report explaining the group's recommendations for corporations, partnerships, estates, trusts and tax administration.
As a young tax lawyer in New York he was part of the Tax Forum, a group of junior tax lawyers that presented papers on tax subjects once a month. Later as a senior lawyer, he was a member of the Tax Club. His participation in the work of the ABA included membership in the Section of Taxation of which he became chairman in 1956 and member of the governing council in 1958. In the 1960s he served on a number of federal advisory groups or task forces: in 1965, President's Johnson Task Force to Improve the World-Wide Competitive Effectiveness of American Business; in 1967, the advisory group for the Commissioner of Internal Revenue; and in 1968, the Task Force on Federal Tax Policy to make recommendations to President-elect Nixon. Between 1968-1971 he worked with the legislators of Virginia, first as a counselor for the Virginia Income Tax Commission, and later as a member of the Virginia Income Tax Conformity Study Commission. In addition Cohen was a member of the American College Tax Counsel, American Judicature Society, D.C. Bar Association, New York State Bar Association, Order of the Coif, Raven Society, Phi Beta Kappa, Omicron Delta Kappa, Phi Delta Epsilon, Phi Epsilon Pi, among many others.
Scope and Content Information
Edwin S. Cohen began donating his papers to the Law Library in 1987. The vast majority of the documents (72 linear feet, or 160 boxes and 2 cartons) document his position as Assistant Secretary of the Treasury for Tax Policy and as Under Secretary of the Treasury for the Nixon administration. In addition there is considerable documentation of his work in private practice and teaching.
Organization
The organization of the collection reflects its original folder headings and arrangement, as well as the sequence in which it was transferred to the library. The files are divided in eight series: the first six relate to Cohen's tenure in the Treasury Department; the seventh concerns teaching and law practice in general; and the eighth (and earliest) series of documents concerns the area of his law practice devoted to the mutual fund industry. The series are organized as follows:
Series I: Tax Reform Act of 1969: 15 boxes
Reports, drafts, letters, including correspondence between Cohen and then-Senator George Bush, memoranda, hearings, etc. related to the Tax Reform Act of 1969.
Series II: General Files: 35 boxes
Drafts, reports, memoranda and correspondence with persons and groups. Subjects include tax policy, depreciation, the Internal Revenue Service, pensions, and tax legislation.
Series III: Foreign Files: 21 boxes
Drafts, reports, memoranda, letters and other papers. Primary subjects are international tax problems, the Domestic Internal Sales Corporation (DISC), and tax treaties.
Series IV: Personal Files: 25 boxes
Congratulatory letters, invitations, personal correspondence and briefing books.
Series V: Miscellaneous Files: 6 boxes
Reports, drafts, memoranda, confidential documents, and some international documents concerning DISC Basic Materials, Alumina Bauxite Pricing, Chilean Expropriation of Copper Mines and international monetary problems. Included are numerous memoranda to the Secretary and Undersecretary of the Treasury as well as for the President and his assistants.
Series VI: Speech Files: 8 boxes
Copies of speeches Cohen gave while at Treasury, some other materials related to the topic or the occasion, and recorded tapes of some speeches.
Series VII: General Private Practice and Law School Files: 17 boxes and 2 cartons
Private practice files which include the cases involving client Hugo Neu, and the merger of the AFL and the NFL, the ABA Advisory Group Papers, and speeches; as well as teaching and personal files. Access to some of this material may be restricted.
Series VIII: National Association of Investments Companies and Investment Company Institute: 28 boxes
Documents concerning Cohen's fifty-year association with the mutual fund industry beginning during his practice with Sullivan & Cromwell. The vast majority of these papers contain materials related to the National Association of Investment Companies (NAIC) and of the Investment Company Institute (ICI).
Contents List
- Tax Reform Act of 1969
  - Tax Reform Act of 1969 [TRA]. Allocation of Deductions. Arbitrage Bonds, 1969 (Box 1)
  - TRA, Capital Gains, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - TRA, Capital Losses, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - TRA, Charitable Contributions, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - TRA, Conglomerate Mergers, 1969 (Box 1)
  - TRA, Cooperatives, 1969 (Box 1)
  - TRA, Contributions, Corporate Rate Deductions, 1969 (Box 2)
  - TRA, Deductions: education, farm losses, hobby losses, moving expenses, 1969 (Box 2)
  - TRA, Deductions and Exemptions, Gore Proposal, 1969, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - TRA, Deductions-Livestock, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - TRA; Deductions and Exemptions-Personal, 1969 (Box 2)
  - TRA, Deferred Compensation, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - TRA, Depletion-Consad Report, 1969 (Box 3)
  - TRA, Depletion-Percentage, 1969-1970, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - TRA, Depletion-Regulations, 1969-1970, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - TRA, Depreciation, Accelerated (Public Utilities), 1969 (Box 4)
  - TRA, Differences between House and Senate Bills, 1969 (Box 4)
  - TRA, Elderly Taxpayers, 1969 (Box 4)
  - TRA, Estate and Gift Taxes, 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - TRA, Foundations-Business Holdings, 1969 (Box 4)
  - TRA, Foundations-Constitutionality, 1969 (Box 4)
  - TRA, Foundations-Definitional Problems, 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - TRA, Foundations-Direct Grants and Political Activities, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - TRA, Foundations-Drafts, letters and memos on policy issues, 1969 (Box 5)
  - TRA, Foundations-Hearings. IRS Administration, 1969 (Box 5)
  - TRA, Foundations-Miscellaneous documents, 1969, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - TRA, Foundations-Peterson Report, 1970 (Box 5)
  - TRA, Foundations-Self Dealing. Tax on Foundations, 1969 (Box 6)
  - TRA, Foundations-Temporary Regulations, 1970 (Box 6)
  - TRA, Foundations, Tentative Drafts 1-22 [missing no. 20], 1969 (Box 6)
  - TRA, Game Plan-Income Averaging, 1969 (Box 6)
  - TRA-General Approach, 1969, folders 1 - 2 of 6 (Box 6)
  - TRA-General Approach, 1969, folders 3 - 6 of 6 (Box 7)
  - TRA, Hearings and Survey, 1969 (Box 8)
  - TRA, Interest. IRS Budget, 1969 (Box 8)
  - TRA, Investment Credit, 1969, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - TRA, Limits on Tax Preferences (LTP), 1969 (Box 8)
  - TRA, Low Income Allowance, 1969 (Box 9)
  - TRA, Maximum Tax on Earned Income. Minimum Income Tax, 1969 (Box 9)
  - TRA-Miscellaneous documents, 1969-1970, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - TRA, Multiple Corporations. Multiple Trusts, 1969 (Box 9)
  - TRA, Municipal Borrowing. Mutual Funds, 1969 (Box 9)
  - TRA, Natural Resources. Natural Resources Production Payments (ABC Transactions and Carved-Out), 1969 (Box 10)
  - TRA, Overpayment and Refunds. Policy Decisions, 1969 (Box 10)
  - TRA, Payment to Government Officials. S 2075, Senator Williams, 1969 (Box 10)
  - TRA, Poverty Incentives, 1969, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - TRA, Poverty Incentives, 1969, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - TRA, Professional Corporations. Press Releases of the Ways and Means Committee, 1969 (Box 11)
  - TRA, Railroad Car Amortization, 1969, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - TRA, Real Estate. Real State Cabinet Committee on Construction, 1969, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - TRA, Receipts, Rate Schedules, Revenue Estimates, 1969-1970, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - TRA, Restricted Stock, 1969 (Box 13)
  - TRA, Senate Amendments, Bills and Hearings, 1969 (Box 13)
  - TRA, Single and Married Taxpayers, 1969 (Box 13)
  - TRA, Stock Dividends, 1969 (Box 13)
  - TRA, Stock Redemptions. Subchapter S Corporations, 1969 (Box 13)
  - TRA-Studies and Proposals Committee Prints, 1969 (Box 14)
  - TRA, Summary of Public Hearings, 1969, April-November, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - TRA, Summaries by TLC of Senate Finance Committee Testimony, 1969 (Box 14)
  - TRA, Surcharge Extension and Repeal of the Investment Tax Credit, 1969 (Box 15)
  - TRA, Tax Exempt Bonds. Arbitrage, Municipal, State and Local, 1969 (Box 15)
  - TRA, Tax Exempt Housing Bonds. Tax Exempt Interest, 1969 (Box 15)
  - TRA, Tax Exempt Organizations, 1969 (Box 15)
  - TRA, Tax Exempt Organizations-Unrelated Business Income, 1969 (Box 15)
  - TRA, Comparison between House and Senate Versions and Provisions Added by Senate, 1969 (Box 15)
  - TRA Proposals. Summary and Technical Explanation, 1969 (Box 15)
- General Files
  - Accumulation Trusts, 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - Advisory Group on Charitable Contributions. Advisory Commission on the Economic Role of Women. Airlines, 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - Aging Study-National Goals Research Staff, 1969 (Box 16)
  - Airway User Tax, 1969-1971 (Box 16)
  - Anti-Pollution Costs, 1967-1969 (Box 16)
  - Antitrust-Treble Damage Deductions, 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - Arbitrage Bonds Provision on the Tax Reform Act, 1970-1972 (Box 16)
  - Armed Forces Combat Zone Tax Regulation, 1969 (Box 16)
  - ATT Bond and Stock Offering, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Audit Review Committee Report, 1969-1971 (Box 16)
  - Bill to amend certain provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 Report, 1968-1972 (Box 17)
  - Budget Message of President Nixon, 1970 (Box 17)
  - Business Council, 1969 (Box 17)
  - Charitable Contributions Deduction Under H.R. 13270. Memo and tables, 1969-1970 (Box 17)
  - Commission to Revise the Tax Structure, 1970-1971 (Box 17)
  - Corporate Stockholder Relationship, 1971 (Box 17)
  - Council on Environmental Quality, 1970-1971 (Box 17)
  - Debt Ceiling Statement and Material, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Department of the Treasury Annual Report of the Secretary, 1969-1972 (Box 17)
  - Depletion-Cutoff Regulations, 1971 (Box 17)
  - Depreciation-ADR [Asset Depreciation Range] System, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Depreciation-ADR Basic Materials, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Depreciation Allowances Using ADR System, 1971, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Depreciation Allowances Using ADR, 1971, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Depreciation-Motion Picture Industry, 1971-1972, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Depreciation Policy, 1969 (Box 19)
  - Depreciation-Public Utilities, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Depreciation- Stauton Law Suit, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Depreciation Studies. 1962 Background, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Depreciation Tax Policy Options, 1970, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Economist Consultants Comments, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Education. Aid to higher education, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Employees Bonus Plans. Earned Income Reorganization, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Excess Profits Tax, 1971 (Box 20)
  - Excise Taxes: autos, tobacco, alcohol, wine, beer, 1969-1972 (Box 21)
  - Face Amount Certificates. Section 1232, 1971-1972, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Federal Budget: 1972-1973, 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Federal Executive Institute, 1969-1972 (Box 21)
  - Federal, State and Local Taxes, 1969-1971 (Box 21)
  - General Accounting Office [GAO] of the IRS Report, 1970 (Box 21)
  - Gifts to the United States, 1970 (Box 21)
  - Hartke-Burke Bill, 1972 (Box 21)
  - Harvard Center for Fiscal Studies. Federal Financing Agency, 1969, 1971 (Box 22)
  - Health and Welfare Funds, 1969-1971 (Box 22)
  - High Income Individual Taxes, 1969-1972, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - H.R. 13334-Treasury Positions Bill, 1972 (Box 22)
  - Income Tax Forms, 1970-1971, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Industrial Development Bonds, 1969-1971, 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Inter-American Center of Tax Administration. Office of Industrial Economies, 1971 (Box 23)
  - Internal Revenue Service [IRS]. Advisory Group to the Commissioner of IRS, 1969-1979 (Box 23)
  - IRS Advisory Committee on Horse and Cattle Industry, 1970-1972 (Box 23)
  - IRS Art Advisory Committee, 1970 (Box 23)
  - IRS Income Tax Returns, Business Statistics of Income, 1969, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - IRS Income Tax Returns, Business Statistics of Income, 1970 (Box 24)
  - IRS Income Tax Returns, Corporations Statistics of Income, 1969, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - IRS Income Tax Returns. Corporations Selected Financial Data 1970, 1972 (Box 24)
  - IRS Income Tax Returns. Individuals. Preliminary Statistics of Income, 1971 (Box 24)
  - IRS-Law Enforcement, 1969-1971 (Box 24)
  - IRS- Manpower, 1969-1971 (Box 24)
  - IRS Memos, 1972 (Box 24)
  - IRS Memos, 1969, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - IRS Memos and News Releases, 1970-1971, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - IRS Publication of Rulings, 1969-1972 (Box 25)
  - IRS Tax Delinquencies, 1970-1972 (Box 25)
  - Investment Tax Credit, 1971-1972 (Box 25)
  - Investment Company Institute Memos (Study of Treasury Law Enforcement Operations), 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Joint Economic Committee Hearings, 1972 (Box 26)
  - Law Enforcement. National Council on Organized Crime, 1970 (Box 26)
  - Leasing. Tax Treatment of Leasing, 1969-1971 (Box 26)
  - Legislative Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Life Insurance Tax Treatment, 1969-1972 (Box 26)
  - Long Term Contracts Regulations, 1972 (Box 26)
  - Litton Industries File, 1968-1970, 3 folders (Box 27)
  - Mass Transit Legislation, 1969 (Box 27)
  - Maximum Tax on Earned Income, 1972 (Box 27)
  - Merchant Marine Industry tax advantages, 1969 (Box 27)
  - Mills Tax Policy Review Act of 1972, 1972 (Box 27)
  - Minimum Tax, 1971-1972 (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous: Moving Expenses Problems, Miscellaneous Task Forces and Study Groups, National Tax Association, Negative Income Tax, 1969 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous Secretary of the Treasury Staff Meetings, 1970-1972, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Motion Pictures. Accounting of film costs, 1971-1972, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - National Economic Research Associates [NERA] Study, 1971 (Box 29)
  - Nolan, John S. [Deputy Assistant Secretary for Tax Policy] Miscellaneous Papers, 1969-1972 (Box 29)
  - Oil and Gas Matters, 1971-1972 (Box 29)
  - Pensions, 1972 (Box 29)
  - Pensions and Profit Sharing, 1970 (Box 29)
  - Pensions Lump Sum Distributions, 1970 (Box 29)
  - Pensions Vesting-Treasury Study, 1969-1974, 5 folders (Box 30)
  - Pensions. Welfare and Pensions Plans Disclosure Act working papers, 1969-1970, 6 folders (Box 31)
  - Pensions Benefits, Security, Issues and Options, 1969 (Box 32)
  - Personal Holding Companies, 1971 (Box 32)
  - Political Contribution Check-Off in 1966-1967 and 1971 Tax Bill, 1971, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - President New Economic Policy, 1971, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - President Nixon Reorganization Plan, 1971 (Box 33)
  - President State of the Union Message. Private Relief, 1969-1970 (Box 33)
  - Press Meetings, 1969-1972 (Box 33)
  - Private Foundations, 1970-1973 (Box 33)
  - Professional Corporations, 1972 (Box 33)
  - Property Tax, 1971 (Box 33)
  - Property Tax Relief, 1972 (Box 33)
  - Public Interest Law Firms Status, 1970 (Box 33)
  - Railroad Transportation Regulations, 1971, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Real Estate Regulations, 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - Report. Research Papers (economists), 1969 (Box 34)
  - Retirement Systems, 1969 (Box 34)
  - Revenue Act of 1969, 1969 (Box 34)
  - Revenue Act of 1971, 1971-1972 (Box 34)
  - Revenue Alternatives and Estimates, 1969-1971, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Revenue and Expenditure Control Act of 1968 (Surcharge and extension of), 1968-1969, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Revenue Estimates, 1970-1972 (Box 35)
  - Revenue Sharing, 1971-1972 (Box 35)
  - Revenue Sharing, 1969-1972, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Secretary Designate Schultz Testimony., 1972 (Box 36)
  - Segregated Schools. Charitable Qualifications, 1969-1970 (Box 36)
  - Segregated Schools. IRS Policy of Racially Discriminatory Private Schools, 1970, 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Segregated Schools. IRS Policy of Racially Discriminatory Private Schools, 1970, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Segregated Schools Tax Status basic materials, 1967-1972 (Box 37)
  - Social Security tax related problems, 1968-1970 (Box 37)
  - Starmount Co. - H.R. 19605 and 1968 by a corporation; Treatment of certain sales of real property, 1966-1970 (Box 37)
  - Statistics of Income. 1971 Advance Data from Individual Income Tax Returns File during 1972, 1971-1972 (Box 37)
  - Subchapter C H.R. 4181. Proposed Amendment to Section 33 of the Code, 1971 (Box 37)
  - Tax Court Forum, 1969 (Box 37)
  - Tax Credit-Education, 1972 (Box 38)
  - Tax Credit- Recycling, 1971-1972 (Box 38)
  - Tax Executives Institute International Recommendations, 1969 (Box 38)
  - Tax Exemption Advertising, 1969 (Box 38)
  - Tax Exempt Bonds, 1970-1972, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Tax Exempt Bonds ss265(2) Banks, 1969-1972, 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Tax Exempt Organizations, 1970-1972, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Tax Exempt Organizations: American Council of Education, 1970 (Box 39)
  - Tax Exempt Organizations: Colleges and universities political activities, 1970 (Box 39)
  - Tax Exempt Organizations Lobbying and Political Activities, 1971-1972, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Tax Exempt Organizations: Political Activities, 1971-1972 (Box 39)
  - Tax Expenditures, 1968-1972 (Box 39)
  - Tax Incentives, 1969-1971 (Box 39)
  - Tax Incentives: Black Caucus Recommendations, 1971 (Box 40)
  - Tax Incentives: Poverty, 1967-1969, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Tax Legislation: Accruing Corporation Income and Excise Tax. Advance Payment. Airway User Bill, 1970 (Box 40)
  - Tax Legislation: Employee Benefits, 1970 (Box 40)
  - Tax Legislation: Cooperatives. Credit Controls, 1970 (Box 41)
  - Tax Legislation: Deadwood Bill, 1970 (Box 41)
  - Tax Legislation: Depletion Regulations. Disclosure of Income Tax Returns, 1979 (Box 41)
  - Tax Legislation: Environmental Tax Incentives, 1970-1971, 2 folders (Box 41)
  - Tax Legislation: Estate and Gift Tax Acceleration of Payments, 1970 (Box 41)
  - Tax Legislation: Estate and Gift Tax Substantive Reforms, 1970, 3 folders (Box 42)
  - Tax Legislation: Family Assistance, 1970 (Box 42)
  - Tax Legislation: Excise Tax Speedup. Flexible Fiscal Policy Act. Foreign Policy, International Taxation, 1970 (Box 42)
  - Tax Legislation: Indian Tribes tax exempts, 1970 (Box 42)
  - Tax Legislation Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 42)
  - Tax Legislation: Miscellaneous. Automobile, Child Care, Elderly, 1971 (Box 43)
  - Tax Legislation: Training Tax Credits, 1969, 3 folders (Box 43)
  - Tax Legislation: Ways and Means Committee, 1970 (Box 43)
  - Tax Legislation drafts, 1971 (Box 43)
  - Tax Legislation: Environmental Proposals, 1971, 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Tax Legislation 1971: Foreign Income, 1970 (Box 44)
  - Tax Legislation 1971: Gambling, 1970 (Box 44)
  - Tax Legislation: Health Care Program, 1971 (Box 44)
  - Tax Legislation: Job Development Credit, 1971-1972 (Box 44)
  - Tax Legislation: Lead Tax, 1970-1971 (Box 44)
  - Tax Legislation: Retirement Income Credit, 1970-1971 (Box 44)
  - Tax Legislation: Sulphur Tax, 1970-1971, 2 folders (Box 44)
  - Tax Legislation: Tax on Excess Wage Increase, 1971 (Box 44)
  - Tax Policy, 1972 (Box 44)
  - Tax Policy Review Act of 1972, 1972 (Box 44)
  - Tax Program: Treasury Proposals on International Taxation, 1971 (Box 44)
  - Tax Program, 1971, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Tax Program Preliminary Briefing Book, 1971 (Box 45)
  - Tax Reform, 1970-1973, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Tax Reform, 1970-1973, 4 folders (Box 46)
  - Tax Reform: Memoranda and Materials, 1972, 2 folders (Box 47)
  - Tax Reform Miscellaneous Documents, 1972 (Box 47)
  - Tax Reform Proposals other than Mills Bill, 1971-1972 (Box 47)
  - Tax Shelters, 1972, 2 folders (Box 48)
  - Taxation Meetings, 1969-1972, 3 folders (Box 48)
  - Telegrams, 1972 (Box 48)
  - Treasury Department Consultants Meetings, 1969-1972 (Box 49)
  - Treasury Department Orders, 1970-1971 (Box 49)
  - Treasury Department Miscellaneous Papers: Inventory of Departmental Budget and Programs. Narcotic Program. Justice Department, 1971 (Box 49)
  - Unemployed Tax Benefits, 1969-1971 (Box 49)
  - Underwithholding Problem. Tax Reform Act of 1969, 1971 (Box 49)
  - Urban Development Act, 1969-1971 (Box 49)
  - Virginia Taxes, 1969-1970 (Box 49)
  - Voter Education Program of the Southern Regional Council, Inc., 1969 (Box 49)
  - Wage-Price Guidelines. Post-freeze economic stabilization program, 1971 (Box 49)
  - Wagering Tax Amendments Proposals, 1969 (Box 49)
  - War Losses and Profits. Welfare Reform Act., 1969 (Box 49)
  - Withholding of Tax Interest on Dividends and Interest, 1960-1972 (Box 50)
  - Withholding, 1969-1972, 3 folders (Box 50)
  - White House Reports, 1969-1971 (Box 50)
  - White House Conference of Children and Youth, 1970 (Box 50)
  - Whipsaw Problem, 1964-1969 (Box 50)
- Foreign Files
  - Bank Accounts: § 452 Accelerated Depreciation on Property. Singapore, 1971 (Box 51)
  - Bank Accounts: Allocation of Income and Deductions-§§ 482, Rev. proc. 64-54. Briefing Book and pertinent publications, 1969-1971, 3 folders (Box 51)
  - Bank Accounts: Policy Committee on Recordkeeping and Reporting by Financial Institutions, 1971, 2 folders (Box 52)